<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ren's Blog - osu!</title><link href="https://blog.rorre.xyz/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.rorre.xyz/feeds/osu.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.rorre.xyz/</id><updated>2020-06-27T20:26:00+07:00</updated><subtitle>osu! Beatmap Nominator</subtitle><entry><title>BN Report: July</title><link href="https://blog.rorre.xyz/posts/bn-report-july/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-27T20:26:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-06-27T20:26:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Rendy Arya Kemal</name></author><id>tag:blog.rorre.xyz,2020-06-27:/posts/bn-report-july/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Upon the creation of this blog, I always wonder as to what I will put here, code updates? life updates? or...something else? Lots of ideas comes up on my mind, but I decided to do something that is a bit related to life updates... but for my life as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Upon the creation of this blog, I always wonder as to what I will put here, code updates? life updates? or...something else? Lots of ideas comes up on my mind, but I decided to do something that is a bit related to life updates... but for my life as a Beatmap Nominator. Let's call it...BN Report!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What? BN Report?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! A monthly BN activity report blog for updates from the stuffs I do as a Beatmap Nominator! But I would like to try to showcase some cool maps that I have nominated too, and pour my thoughts into it, similar to how osu!'s spotlight works. I would like to let everyone knows about what I've been doing in a month, and also share my thoughts on things happening.&lt;br&gt;
Aside from that, updates about my requests site will also be listed here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you be reacting to dramas in this blog though?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. I usually keep my opinions on dramas in a closed space, but sometimes I also pour my thoughts in my Twitter, but it doesn't happen often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are you doing this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm bored, I guess. I also want to learn how to write things too as I am horrible at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, without further ado, let's go to the main point of this post, the report itself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="ui divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;BN Report: Last week of May and June&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last week of May and June is in one post because I want to start right after my last evaluation, which happens last month.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright! Last week of May and June has been quite a ride for me, coding the requests site, doing bn work, etc. It's quite hard to manage my time but I did it. So, let's get started with the updates from the site itself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Requests Site Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can now see when did your request got updated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple requests is now disabled.&lt;/strong&gt; This is due to the fact that people seem to abuse this and just send all of their maps to me. Leaving feedback for all of them seems very redundant to do especially if such overaching issues is present to all of the maps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"My requests" page is now using table instead of card.&lt;/strong&gt; I'm sure you all don't like hovering to the "Why?" button everytime you see your map gets rejected. &lt;em&gt;This will change in the future to use popups, it's still in the works.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pagination is now available.&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, we all don't like to see a billion maps in one page. It also consumes an unnecessary amount of memory to hold them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can now see the maps that is going to get nominated and it's status.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-nominator support is here.&lt;/strong&gt; Hell yes, this site is now work with more than one nominator! If you're a nominator and would like to use this site, feel free to contact me! At the moment, Raiden is now another valid option for the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of requests site--It is now &lt;strong&gt;open for reqs for the next 24h!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nominator Life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past 2 months has been quite a ride, I saw a lot of request with a huge variety of styles and genres, and I must say, it was nice to see more genre other than "Anime Japanese"! It feels really freshing to see that there are more and more of non-Japanese things coming to me, as I'm fine with any genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I have nominated 15 maps in the past 5 weeks, a pretty decent number I'd say, considering in the past I've been quite dead in the BNG, and being active again is quite nice. I'm looking forward to have better activity and be more consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Spotlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, here are the maps that I feel like they're quite cool to look at!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="ui divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Tove Styrke - Change My Mind [Mint + schoolboy]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="ui segment"&gt;
    &lt;img class="ui centered fluid image" src="https://assets.ppy.sh/beatmaps/982452/covers/cover@2x.jpg?1590165486"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/2407160"&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt; (formerly known as appleeaterx) is back again with a simple, yet really pleasing to play map, but this time they have &lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/8722791"&gt;schoolboy&lt;/a&gt; with them, which makes it even more interesting! The slow slider velocity on top diff and how they structure their maps looks pretty satisfying to play and look at. I absolutely recommend you to play the set if you're looking for some easy snappy-aim challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="ui divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;100 gecs - ringtone (remix) [Haruto + smh + Ancelysia + tomadoi + Agatsu]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="ui segment"&gt;
    &lt;img class="ui centered fluid image" src="https://assets.ppy.sh/beatmaps/1117775/covers/cover@2x.jpg?1590461435"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/3772301"&gt;Haruto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/5712451"&gt;tricolor&lt;/a&gt; (aka tomadoi), &lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/5579871"&gt;Agatsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/1629553"&gt;smh&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/7118575"&gt;Ancelysia&lt;/a&gt; brings out a banger by 100 gecs to the ranked section, with each diffs having its very own style, that makes the gameplay quite unique to play for each of their own.&lt;br&gt;
Added to that, we see two new names in the ranked section, with &lt;code&gt;smh&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Ancelysia&lt;/code&gt; having their first ranked difficulty in this game! I hope to see more of them in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="ui divider"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Plutian - Until the Blue Moon Rises [ktgster]&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="ui segment"&gt;
    &lt;img class="ui centered fluid image" src="https://assets.ppy.sh/beatmaps/995205/covers/cover@2x.jpg?1590634071"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/53378"&gt;ktgster&lt;/a&gt; has always been quite a unique mapper, trying to do new things in each of their own map, and this is no exception! We see low AR diffs that is quite unique for current era to get ranked, with the top diff being AR0, making everything looks like it's slapped on your monitor. This makes quite a challenging experience, especially for those of you who aren't familiar with low AR to read the map. If you're quite new to reading low AR, you could use this map as your training point, as the map itself is actually really simple and very straightforward to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That concludes my first post for this monthly blog post! I will try do this consistently for every last week of the month. But for now, I'll see ya guys in the next post!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="osu!"></category><category term="osu"></category><category term="bn"></category><category term="mapping"></category><category term="modding"></category></entry><entry><title>Changing How Requests Works</title><link href="https://blog.rorre.xyz/posts/why-requests-site/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-22T11:45:00+07:00</published><updated>2020-05-22T11:45:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Rendy Arya Kemal</name></author><id>tag:blog.rorre.xyz,2020-05-22:/posts/why-requests-site/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;During mapping, there are just times where you want to rank your map. You may even be actually actively ranking a map right now. However, the current process requires 2 BNs to rank a map. This is where it could get tricky and/or frustrating. Requesting BNs has (and maybe …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During mapping, there are just times where you want to rank your map. You may even be actually actively ranking a map right now. However, the current process requires 2 BNs to rank a map. This is where it could get tricky and/or frustrating. Requesting BNs has (and maybe always will be,) something that frustrates mappers for many reasons; whether BNs are simply closed or just ignore you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="ui icon warning message"&gt;
  &lt;i class="exclamation triangle icon"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="header"&gt;
      This post is filled with opinions.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most of the stuff I wrote are things that I know from experience, or from others. It is filled with quite a bit of subjectivity, so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Problems in Requesting BNs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, let's say you are done with your map, gathered mods, and ready to rank it. You will now need to get 2 BNs for it. It sounds just fine by just looking at the paper, but in reality you will encounter many problems that blocks your way. Here's some common problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Too many closed BNs.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, let's say you're in the BN listing page, either on &lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/groups/28"&gt;osu!'s group listing&lt;/a&gt; or in &lt;a href="https://bn.mappersguild.com/"&gt;the BN site&lt;/a&gt;, you click on every single bn, and you see nearly everyone is closed. While totally have the rights to close for reqs, sometimes you just keep wandering how come so many BNs are closed, heck, some of them are even closed for more than a month! Especially if the BNs that are open reject your map outright from their rules, it is just frustrating. What the hell are they doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. You keep getting ignored.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, getting ignored &lt;strong&gt;sucks&lt;/strong&gt;. You never know if the BN actually ever checked your map or not, let alone downloading it. But at the same time, they could be getting lots of PMs. I must admit I did ignore lots of people whenever they requested me. I mean...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="https://d.rorre.xyz/FkUlgP/chrome_xHt36PNdrn.png"&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I clearly didn't do my best and actually reply to them, and some of the messages are now 4-5 months old. It is still frustrating how easily BNs can just ignore you, and I totally get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Getting rejected for no reason.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You finally get to contact a BN! Good job on that, whether its on queue or by PM. But now there's another problem coming: you either get accepted, or rejected. If you get rejected, sometimes they don't really have any particular reason, they just put in "idk don't look too good for me" or something along the line of it without even bothering to look at the map at all. This will leave you in a completely confused state, as you won't know what exactly the problem was. If you then go on to ask multiple BNs and they all reject you the same, you will just get even more confused. Why do you keep getting rejected?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. You don't have the balls to PM a BN.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, this happens to most of us. There's no need of an explanation for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Requests Site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://bn.rorre.xyz/"&gt;Link to the site itself.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that some of the big issues are in there, let's look at the site itself, what's the goal, and what's the disadvantages of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Goals and Mechanics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the site is to reduce the frustation of requesting the BNs itself. Yes, I know I am the only one using this method, but that doesn't mean other's cant using other method that has the same goal. How do I fix these problems? Here's how!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the site, you can directly see how many requests do I get, the maps, and their respective statuses, whether it's pending or accepted. (Rejected will be thrown away from public and only the requester can see.) This is similar to how BN Trello works, except all the requests and inputs are done by the requester itself, and they can cancel the request anytime they want (they may already have 2 BNs or they just want to mess around). The site also features all past accepted requests, showing how much requests have I modded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only that, if you join my Discord Server, you can see all the feed of requests getting in, updates to it, etc. in real time! This gives people information as to what the hell I have been doing, whether I'm just slacking off all this time or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the case of rejected requests, the requester will always get a reason as to why is it rejected, whether it's caused by personal preference (aka "I don't like how you structure the map" or "I don't like movement mapping") or if it's caused by the map having actual fundamental issues. The requester should now be able to understand as to why their request is rejected and maybe, improve their beatmap before going on to ask other BNs (or they can just ask other BNs because everyone has different opinion on something).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="https://d.rorre.xyz/2LGoYK/DUe9J5FGRC.png"&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thing, of course, is not perfect, there are disadvantages for both requester and the BN (in this case, me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;For requester&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It may take more time for the BN to respond&lt;/strong&gt;. Writing feedback to them sometimes is hard, you need to pick out words that is easily understandable for the requester to understand and sometimes there are just too many requests to scroll through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The reasoning may not satisfy you&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, I am fully aware of this happening and people shittalking over the reasoning of rejection, especially when it comes to personal taste. However I cannot help but see this happening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;For the BN&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Giving feedback is hard&lt;/strong&gt;. Especially if the map is fundamentally flawed in the first place, sometimes you don't know where to start with and keeps staring at the feedback textbox for quite some time just to think about what will you write so that they understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People could mald on your reasoning&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, we all know this will happen sometime later, and someone will bring this up to twitter/reddit/discord server/whatever and may cause some drama to happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not listing things like server cost etc because I feel like its not a huge deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, the requests site has been up and running for 2 weeks with only one batch done, and I still need to review some maps, I got 36 reqs and have accepted 11 reqs, 12 pending, and 13 rejected. I will try to use the site for the next couple batch and see how it's going. Whether it's going for the better (for me and the requesters) or it's actually worsen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts are absolutely welcome! I'm very glad if you have some critics and suggestions to improve this thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="ui segment"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many thanks to &lt;a href="https://osu.ppy.sh/users/8819496"&gt;mindmaster107&lt;/a&gt; for proofreading and rewriting this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="osu!"></category><category term="osu"></category><category term="bn"></category></entry></feed>